Uh, the previous query finished
and uh, it just took about three minutes.
Look at the data scan.
Four 40 point 14 mb
and if you go back to the S3 data lake for the month of
February and year 2095,
the file contains exactly four 40.2 mb, which means
that when we fired this query with the filter, just
that particular folder alone was scanned.
Okay? So our next step is to have a table for uh,
the zone lookup file, right?
It'll go back to the glue catalog lock, we'll go
to crawler in fact and create to
and name it as mission.
D-E-H-H-O-F-N-Y-C-T-L-C
Zone.
And then next, and then add the data source,
provide the location, the path where the zone file exists.
So we're gonna go here, click on this and copy that. S3 URI.
Go back to the crawler, provide the path right here.
Click on this error itself
and then click on add data source.
Scroll down and then next, use the role
that your team load has team lead has provided to you.
Okay? And then do one next.
Choose the same database, which also hosts our other table,
which is mission, D-H-H-O-F-N-Y, CT LC.
This time, leave it blank, blank the table,
Tix and then go to next.
And then scroll down, review the whole thing.
Click, click on, create color. It's all done.
Now we can simply run the crawler. It is now running.
We can refresh it here. It took a minute.
If we're all done now we scroll to the right,
it shows one table change.
Now this might take about a few seconds to
show up here to have patience.
It says table added zone.
If you go to the database again, click on that,
click on database here.
You'll now see the second table, the zone right here.
And if I click on the table data right here,
it'll take me to Athena.
Click on proceed. And there you go.
The query is ready for us and it is already filed
and data is getting scanned
and you should see soon see the data here.
And now on the left hand side,
you see the zone table shows up right here within the
database and you expand this.
This has the pickup location ID and drop location id.
And if I scroll down the zone has the location id,
so the data analyst can really join this table, the
H-V-F-H-V-H-V-F-H-V with the zone table.
Based on the location ID
to get information about the borough zone.
And again, talking about the joins and stuff.
I hope you now have watched the sequel skill booster
course and then come back here.
You should now see the data right here from the file we saw.
And if you don't see this and if,
if it shows it's spinning up here,
just go and refresh the page.
It'll show up right here. So we've got two tables now the
analyst can now join both the tables
and then you then talk to the cloud engineer team and
Check with them. If
the analyst can AC query the zone table, you say yes,
then you go and inform your analyst team that yes,
I have created the zone table.
You can now go ahead and query that.
I also have added a lot of data that you asked me
to add from 2024 till 25.
All data is in S3, it's in partition format.
You can now use the filters year and month.
That will speed up your query, do your analysis
and let me know the next steps.
That is what you'll say.